Guide to the M. L. Rosenthal Papers ca. 1930-1996 MSS 45 MSS.045
Fales Library and Special Collections
M. L. Rosenthal Papers
ca. 1930-1996
Fales Library and Special Collections
MSS.045
50 Linear Feet (36 boxes)
Macha Louis Rosenthal (1917-1996), poet, critic, editor, and teacher, earned a Ph.D. at New York University where he was a professor of English until 1996. He also served as director of the Poetics Institute at NYU. Besides publishing numerous books of criticism, collections of verse and contributing poetry, articles and reviews to The New Yorker, Poetry, the Spectator, he served in the U.S. Cultural Exchange Program from 1961-1980 and was a visiting specialist to Germany, Pakistan, Romania, Poland, and Bulgaria, Italy and France. He also was poetry editor of The Nation, the Humanist, and Present Tense and edited various anthologies of poetry. The collection is comprised of the correspondence, manuscripts and subject files of many notable literary figures; the manuscripts and business/production files for Rosenthal's scholarly books, essays, poetry, reviews, and lectures; journals, offprints, and other printed materials; biographical material; photographs; and audiovisual material.
Provenance
The M. L. Rosenthal Papers were donated in October 1996 by Victoria Rosenthal. The initial organization of the collection was done by Sally M. Gall, student and colleague of Rosenthal.
Access Restrictions
Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Fales Library and Special Collections, fales.library@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596.
Historical/Biographical Note
Macha Louis Rosenthal, poet, critic, editor, and teacher, was born on March 14, 1917 in Washington, D. C. He took his B.A. (1937) and M.A. (1938) degrees at the University of Chicago. On January 7, 1939, he married Victoria Himmelstein with whom he had three children: David, Alan, and Laura. From 1939 to 1945, he taught as an instructor in English at Michigan State University. In 1946, he was hired as an instructor at New York University, where he earned his Ph.D. in 1949. In 1961, he served in the U.S. Cultural Exchange Program and was visiting specialist to Germany; in 1965, to Pakistan; in 1966, to Romania, Poland, and Bulgaria, and in 1980, to Italy and France. In 1974, he was a visiting poet in Israel. From 1977 to 1979 he served as director of the Poetics Institute at New York University where he was a professor of English until 1996. He was a fellow of the American Council of Learned Societies and twice won Guggenheim Fellowships (1960-1964). He contributed poems, articles, and reviews to such leading journals as The New Yorker, the New Statesman, Poetry, the Spectator (London), ELH, and the Quarterly Review of Literature; he also served, from 1956-1961, as poetry editor of The Nation, from 1970-1978 as poetry editor of the Humanist, and from 1973-1990 as poetry editor of Present Tense. He published numerous books of criticism and collections of verse and edited various anthologies of poetry. M. L. Rosenthal died on July 21, 1996.
Scope and Content Note
The M. L. Rosenthal Papers is comprised of the correspondence, manuscripts and subject files of many notable literary figures; the manuscripts and business/production files for Rosenthal's scholarly books, essays, poetry, reviews, and lectures; journals, offprints, and other printed materials; biographical material; photographs; and audiovisual material. The M. L. Rosenthal Papers contains a comprehensive collection of the early to late literary career of M. L. Rosenthal. Sally M. Gall's original organization of Rosenthal's papers was preserved as much as possible.
SERIES DESCRIPTION
SERIES I: Correspondence: contains 2 boxes of correspondence with such important literary figures as William Carlos Williams, Ted Hughes, Robert Creeley, Christopher Grieve, Laura Riding Jackson, Muriel Rukeyser, and many others. It also contains family correspondence with Rosenthal's wife, Vicki, and his two sons, David and Alan.
SERIES II: Manuscripts: contains 3 boxes of manuscripts by Paul Blackburn, Kenneth Burke, Ramon Guthrie, Ted Hughes, Muriel Rukeyser, James Schevill, Grace Schulman, Theodore Weiss, and William Carlos Williams, among many others.
SERIES III: Subject Files: contains 2 boxes of subject files providing background information, notes, reviews, articles, etc. on the literary figures with which Rosenthal corresponded or studied. Subseries B contains 2 boxes of general subject files on various topics of interest for Rosenthal.
SERIES IV: M. L. Rosenthal's Writing: contains 6 boxes of Rosenthal's manuscripts and other book-related files, arranged chronologically by book. All materials related to each book are kept together, including later editions. Subseries B contains 4 boxes of Rosenthal's manuscripts for poems, essays, reviews and lectures, often in several drafts.
SERIES V: Printed Material: subseries A contains 2 boxes of the journals and other publications that include entries by Rosenthal. Subseries B contains 2 boxes of offprints and other miscellaneous printed material by authors other than Rosenthal.
SERIES VI: Biographical Material: contains 8 boxes of biographical materials including juvenilia, college materials, notebooks, teaching notes, syllabi, student papers, and other course-related materials pertaining to Rosenthal's teaching career. It also contains programs and playbills from various events he attended, information and souvenirs from places he traveled, and paperwork from grants and programs for which he applied. Box 1 of Series VI contains the most important biographical material, including articles about M. L. Rosenthal. Box 7 of Series 6 is a small gray box holding Rosenthal's address books and planners. Box 8 of Series 6 contains accretions from Rosenthal's office at the English Department and materials found in Rosenthal's books while cataloguing them at Fales.
SERIES VII: Production Files: contains 2 boxes of production files for several of Rosenthal's books, arranged alphabetically by book title.
SERIES VIII: Photographs: contains 1 small black box of photographs of Rosenthal, his family, and other miscellaneous group photographs.
SERIES IX: Audiovisual Files: contains 1 letter box of cassette tapes of readings and other miscellaneous recording, reel-to-reel tape, and one microfilm. [Research copies may not be available for these materials yet. Check with the Fales archivist.]
OVERSIZE: There is 1 flat oversize box that contains oversize materials from series 5 and 6.
Arrangement
Folders are arranged alphabetically by subject and author heading.
The files are grouped into 9 series and subdivided into subseries.
Missing Title
Series I: Correspondence
Series II: Manuscripts
Series III: Subject Files
Series IV: M.L. Rosenthal's Writing
Series V: Printed Material
Series VI: Biographical Material
Series VII: Production Files
Series VIII: Photographs
Series IX: Audiovisual
Oversize
Separated Material
The M. L. Rosenthal Library, comprising some 5,000 titles, was donated to the NYU libraries along with the papers. The library was sorted, primary texts were catalogued for the Fales Library, secondary texts were sent to the open stacks.
Articles.; Photographs; Journals (periodicals); Audiotapes.; Correspondence.; American poetry |y 20th century.; Lecture notes.; Authors, American.; Ephemera; Syllabi.; Address books.; Juvenilia.; American poetry |y 20th century |x History and criticism.; Authors and publishers -- United States.; Reviews (document genre); Manuscripts for publication.; Notebooks.; Literature |x Study and teaching.; American literature |y 20th century.; Poets, American.; Williams, William Carlos, 1883-1963; Ginsberg, Allen, 1926-1997; Weiss, Theodore Russell, 1916-; Schulman, Grace; Schevill, James Erwin, 1920-; Rukeyser, Muriel, 1913-1980; Rosenthal, M. L. (Macha Louis), 1917-; Pound, Ezra, 1885-1972; MacDiarmid, Hugh, 1892-1978; Guthrie, Ramon, 1896-1973; Hughes, Ted, 1930-1998; Jackson, Laura (Riding), 1901-1991; Kermode, Frank, 1919-; Kinsella, Thomas; Moore, Marianne, 1887-1972; New York University; Amis, Kingsley; Blackburn, Paul; Burke, Kenneth, 1897-1993; Creeley, Robert, 1926-2005; Dickey, James; Ferlinghetti, Lawrence
- Series I: Correspondence
  - A, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Abse, Dannie, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Alvarez, Al, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Amichai, Yehuda, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Amis, Kingsley, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - B, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Blackburn, Paul, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Boutelle, Annie, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Brooke-Rose, Christine, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Burke, France, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Burke, Kenneth, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Bush, Douglas, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - C, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Capouya, Emile, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Cargill, Oscar, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Carmi, T., undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Ciardi, John, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Clarke, Austin, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Creeley, Robert, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - D, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Davie, Donald, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Dicker, Harold, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Dickey, James, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Donoghue, Denis, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Duncan, Robert, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - E, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Eberhart, Richard, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Eliot, T. S., undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - F, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Fauchereau, Serge, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Fearing, Kenneth, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Feirstein, Fred, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Ferlinghetti, Laurence, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Finlay, Ian Hamilton, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Fueloep-Miller, Erika, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - G, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Gall, Sally M., undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Galler, David, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Ginsberg, Allen and Louis, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Greene, David, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Gregory, Horace, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Gregory, Marya, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Grieve, Christopher, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Gover, Philip, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Guthrie, Ramon, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - H, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Hall, Donald, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Harrison, Jim, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Holloway, John, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Horovitz, Michael, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Hoskins, Katherine, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Hughes, Ted, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Humphries, Rolfe, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - I, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - J, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - K, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Keane, Patrick, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Kermode, Frank, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Kinnell, Galway, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Kinsella, Thomas, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Kizer, Carolyn, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - L, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Laing, Alexander, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Laing, Dilys, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Laughlin, James, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Levertov, Denise, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Lowell, Robert, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - M, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Mc, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - MacManus, Frank, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Mann, Thomas, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - May, James Boyer, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Merwin, W. S., undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Montague, John, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Moore, Marianne, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Mottram, Eric, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Muir, Edwin, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Murphy, Richard, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - N, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Nemerov, Howard, undated; 31142040611926 (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - O, undated; 31142040612015 (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Olney, James, undated; 31142040612015 (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Olson, Charles, undated; 31142040612015 (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - P, undated; 31142040612015 (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - Pound, Ezra, undated; 31142040612015 (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - Q, undated; 31142040612015 (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - R, undated; 31142040612015 (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - Redgrove, Peter, undated; 31142040612015 (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - Rago, Henry, undated; 31142040612015 (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - Riding, Laura (Jackson), undated; 31142040612015 (Box 2, Folder 90)
  - Ridler, Anne, undated; 31142040612015 (Box 2, Folder 91)
  - Rudman, Mark, undated; 31142040612015 (Box 2, Folder 92)
  - Rukeyser, Muriel, undated; 31142040612015 (Box 2, Folder 93)
  - S, undated; 31142040612015 (Box 2, Folder 94)
  - Schevill, James, undated; 31142040612015 (Box 2, Folder 95)
  - Schulman, Grace, undated; 31142040612015 (Box 2, Folder 96)
  - Scott, Winfield Townley, undated; 31142040612015 (Box 2, Folder 97)
  - Shapiro, Karl, undated; 31142040612015 (Box 2, Folder 98)
  - Smith, A. J. M., undated; 31142040612015 (Box 2, Folder 99)
  - Spender, Stephen, undated; 31142040612015 (Box 2, Folder 100)
  - Swenson, May, undated; 31142040612015 (Box 2, Folder 101)
  - T, undated; 31142040612015 (Box 2, Folder 102)
  - Tomlinson, Charles, undated; 31142040612015 (Box 2, Folder 103)
  - V, undated; 31142040612015 (Box 2, Folder 104)
  - W, undated; 31142040612015 (Box 2, Folder 105)
  - Weber, Richard, undated; 31142040612015 (Box 2, Folder 106)
  - Weiss, Theodore, undated; 31142040612015 (Box 2, Folder 107)
  - Whittemore, Reed, undated; 31142040612015 (Box 2, Folder 108)
  - Wilbur, Richard, undated; 31142040612015 (Box 2, Folder 109)
  - Williams, Jonathan, undated; 31142040612015 (Box 2, Folder 110)
  - Williams, William Carlos, undated; 31142040612015 (Box 2, Folder 111)
  - Wright, David, undated; 31142040612015 (Box 2, Folder 112)
  - XYZ, undated; 31142040612015 (Box 2, Folder 113)
  - Chinese correspondence, undated; 31142040612015 (Box 2, Folder 114)
  - Family correspondence, undated; 31142040612015 (Box 2, Folder 115)
  - Italian correspondence, undated; 31142040612015 (Box 2, Folder 116)
  - Correspondence from MLR, undated; 31142040612015 (Box 2, Folder 117)
  - Correspondence from MLR to Vicky, undated; 31142040612015 (Box 2, Folder 118)
  - Correspondence from MLR to Vicky, undated; 31142040612015 (Box 2, Folder 119)
  - Unidentified correspondence, undated; 31142040612015 (Box 2, Folder 120)
- Series II: Manuscripts
  - A, undated; 31142040612023 (Box II.1, Folder 1)
  - Abse, Dannie, undated; 31142040612023 (Box II.1, Folder 2)
  - Alvarez, Al, undated; 31142040612023 (Box II.1, Folder 3)
  - Amichai, Yehuda, undated; 31142040612023 (Box II.1, Folder 4)
  - B, undated; 31142040612023 (Box II.1, Folder 5)
  - Barnstone, Willis, undated; 31142040612023 (Box II.1, Folder 6)
  - Barnstone, Willis, undated; 31142040612023 (Box II.1, Folder 7)
  - Blackburn, Paul, undated; 31142040612023 (Box II.1, Folder 8)
  - Burke, France, undated; 31142040612023 (Box II.1, Folder 9)
  - Burke, Kenneth, undated; 31142040612023 (Box II.1, Folder 10)
  - Burnshaw, Stanley, undated; 31142040612023 (Box II.1, Folder 11)
  - C, undated; 31142040612023 (Box II.1, Folder 12)
  - Cameron, Kenneth Neill, undated; 31142040612023 (Box II.1, Folder 13)
  - Cargill, Oscar, undated; 31142040612023 (Box II.1, Folder 14)
  - Carmi, T., undated; 31142040612023 (Box II.1, Folder 15)
  - Creeley, Robert, undated; 31142040612023 (Box II.1, Folder 16)
  - D, undated; 31142040612023 (Box II.1, Folder 17)
  - Davie, Donald, undated; 31142040612023 (Box II.1, Folder 18)
  - Diamond, Stanley, undated; 31142040612023 (Box II.1, Folder 19)
  - Dicker, Harold, undated; 31142040612023 (Box II.1, Folder 20)
  - Doyle, Charles, undated; 31142040612023 (Box II.1, Folder 21)
  - Duncan, Robert, undated; 31142040612023 (Box II.1, Folder 22)
  - Eberhart, Richard, undated; 31142040612023 (Box II.1, Folder 23)
  - Evans, George (ed.), undated; 31142040612023 (Box II.1, Folder 24)
  - Evans, George (ed.), undated; 31142040612023 (Box II.1, Folder 25)
  - Evans, George (ed.), undated; 31142040612023 (Box II.1, Folder 26)
  - Evans, George (ed.), undated; 31142040612023 (Box II.1, Folder 27)
  - F, undated; 31142040612023 (Box II.1, Folder 28)
  - Fields, Scott, undated; 31142040612023 (Box II.1, Folder 29)
  - Feirstein, Fred, undated; 31142040612023 (Box II.1, Folder 30)
  - Feirstein, Fred, undated; 31142040612023 (Box II.1, Folder 31)
  - G, undated; 31142040612031 (Box II.2, Folder 32)
  - Gall, Sally M., undated; 31142040612031 (Box II.2, Folder 33)
  - Gall, Sally M., undated; 31142040612031 (Box II.2, Folder 34)
  - Ginsberg, Allen, undated; 31142040612031 (Box II.2, Folder 35)
  - Grover, Philip, undated; 31142040612031 (Box II.2, Folder 36)
  - Guthrie, Ramon, undated; 31142040612031 (Box II.2, Folder 37)
  - Guthrie, Ramon, undated; 31142040612031 (Box II.2, Folder 38)
  - H, undated; 31142040612031 (Box II.2, Folder 39)
  - Harrison, Jim, undated; 31142040612031 (Box II.2, Folder 40)
  - Horowitz, Michael, undated; 31142040612031 (Box II.2, Folder 41)
  - Hughes, Ted, undated; 31142040612031 (Box II.2, Folder 42)
  - I, undated; 31142040612031 (Box II.2, Folder 43)
  - J, undated; 31142040612031 (Box II.2, Folder 44)
  - K, undated; 31142040612031 (Box II.2, Folder 45)
  - Keane, Patrick, undated; 31142040612031 (Box II.2, Folder 46)
  - Kinsella, Thomas, undated; 31142040612031 (Box II.2, Folder 47)
  - L, undated; 31142040612031 (Box II.2, Folder 48)
  - Laing, Alexander, undated; 31142040612031 (Box II.2, Folder 49)
  - Laing, Dilys, undated; 31142040612031 (Box II.2, Folder 50)
  - M, undated; 31142040612031 (Box II.2, Folder 51)
  - Mc, undated; 31142040612031 (Box II.2, Folder 52)
  - Merriam, Eve, undated; 31142040612031 (Box II.2, Folder 53)
  - Montague, John, undated; 31142040612031 (Box II.2, Folder 54)
  - Murphy, Richard, undated; 31142040612031 (Box II.2, Folder 55)
  - N, undated; 31142040612031 (Box II.2, Folder 56)
  - Nemerov, Harold, undated; 31142040612031 (Box II.2, Folder 57)
  - O, undated; 31142040612031 (Box II.2, Folder 58)
  - P, undated; 31142040612031 (Box II.2, Folder 59)
  - Pagis, Dan, undated; 31142040612031 (Box II.2, Folder 60)
  - Poetry Group (1971-72), 1971-1972; 31142040612031 (Box II.2, Folder 61)
  - Q, undated; 31142040612031 (Box II.2, Folder 62)
  - R, undated; 31142040612049 (Box II.3, Folder 63)
  - Raimes, James, undated; 31142040612049 (Box II.3, Folder 64)
  - Redgrove (the group), undated; 31142040612049 (Box II.3, Folder 65)
  - Redgrove, Peter, undated; 31142040612049 (Box II.3, Folder 66)
  - Rosenthal, David, undated; 31142040612049 (Box II.3, Folder 67)
  - Rudnick, Raphael, undated; 31142040612049 (Box II.3, Folder 68)
  - Rukeyser, Muriel, undated; 31142040612049 (Box II.3, Folder 69)
  - S, undated; 31142040612049 (Box II.3, Folder 70)
  - Schevill, James, undated; 31142040612049 (Box II.3, Folder 71)
  - Schulman, Grace, undated; 31142040612049 (Box II.3, Folder 72)
  - Scott, Winfield Townley, undated; 31142040612049 (Box II.3, Folder 73)
  - Scott, Winfield Townley, undated; 31142040612049 (Box II.3, Folder 74)
  - Scott, Winfield Townley, undated; 31142040612049 (Box II.3, Folder 75)
  - Seferis, George, undated; 31142040612049 (Box II.3, Folder 76)
  - Smith, A. J. M., undated; 31142040612049 (Box II.3, Folder 77)
  - Sommer, undated; 31142040612049 (Box II.3, Folder 78)
  - Stanford, Ann, undated; 31142040612049 (Box II.3, Folder 79)
  - Stevens, Wallace, undated; 31142040612049 (Box II.3, Folder 80)
  - T, undated; 31142040612049 (Box II.3, Folder 81)
  - Tomlinson, Charles, undated; 31142040612049 (Box II.3, Folder 82)
  - V, undated; 31142040612049 (Box II.3, Folder 83)
  - W, undated; 31142040612049 (Box II.3, Folder 84)
  - Weber, Richard, undated; 31142040612049 (Box II.3, Folder 85)
  - Weiss, Theodore, undated; 31142040612049 (Box II.3, Folder 86)
  - Williams, William Carlos, undated; 31142040612049 (Box II.3, Folder 87)
  - Wolf, Leonard, undated; 31142040612049 (Box II.3, Folder 88)
  - Wright, David, undated; 31142040612049 (Box II.3, Folder 89)
  - XYZ, undated; 31142040612049 (Box II.3, Folder 90)
  - Unidentified mss., undated; 31142040612049 (Box II.3, Folder 91)
- Series III: Subject Files
  - Subseries A: writers and artists
    - A, undated; 31142040612056 (Box III.A.1, Folder 1)
    - Abse, Dannie, undated; 31142040612056 (Box III.A.1, Folder 2)
    - Alvarez, Al, undated; 31142040612056 (Box III.A.1, Folder 3)
    - Auden, W. H., undated; 31142040612056 (Box III.A.1, Folder 4)
    - B, undated; 31142040612056 (Box III.A.1, Folder 5)
    - Berryman, John, undated; 31142040612056 (Box III.A.1, Folder 6)
    - Betjeman, John, undated; 31142040612056 (Box III.A.1, Folder 7)
    - Blackburn, Paul, undated; 31142040612056 (Box III.A.1, Folder 8)
    - Bloom, Harold, undated; 31142040612056 (Box III.A.1, Folder 9)
    - Borges, J. L., undated; 31142040612056 (Box III.A.1, Folder 10)
    - Brecht, Bertold, undated; 31142040612056 (Box III.A.1, Folder 11)
    - Burke, France, undated; 31142040612056 (Box III.A.1, Folder 12)
    - Burke, Kenneth, undated; 31142040612056 (Box III.A.1, Folder 13)
    - C, undated; 31142040612056 (Box III.A.1, Folder 14)
    - Capouya, Emile, undated; 31142040612056 (Box III.A.1, Folder 15)
    - Cargill, Oscar, undated; 31142040612056 (Box III.A.1, Folder 16)
    - Creeley, Robert, undated; 31142040612056 (Box III.A.1, Folder 17)
    - D, undated; 31142040612056 (Box III.A.1, Folder 18)
    - Dickinson, Emily, undated; 31142040612056 (Box III.A.1, Folder 19)
    - Dicker, Harold, undated; 31142040612056 (Box III.A.1, Folder 20)
    - Dickey, James, undated; 31142040612056 (Box III.A.1, Folder 21)
    - Duncan, Robert, undated; 31142040612056 (Box III.A.1, Folder 22)
    - E, undated; 31142040612056 (Box III.A.1, Folder 23)
    - Eberhart, Richard, undated; 31142040612056 (Box III.A.1, Folder 24)
    - Eliot, T. S., undated; 31142040612056 (Box III.A.1, Folder 25)
    - Eliot, T. S., undated; 31142040612056 (Box III.A.1, Folder 26)
    - F, undated; 31142040612056 (Box III.A.1, Folder 27)
    - Finlay, Ian Hamilton, undated; 31142040612056 (Box III.A.1, Folder 28)
    - Frost, Robert, undated; 31142040612056 (Box III.A.1, Folder 29)
    - G, undated; 31142040612056 (Box III.A.1, Folder 30)
    - Gall, Sally M., undated; 31142040612056 (Box III.A.1, Folder 31)
    - Ghalib, Mirza, undated; 31142040612056 (Box III.A.1, Folder 32)
    - Ginsberg, Allen and Louis, undated; 31142040612056 (Box III.A.1, Folder 33)
    - Graves, Robert, undated; 31142040612056 (Box III.A.1, Folder 34)
    - Gregory, Horace, undated; 31142040612056 (Box III.A.1, Folder 35)